Guide to the Donald Gordon Papers, 1900-1988 UA.90.F46
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Modern Art Exhibitions, 1900-1916, II.
  - New York, January 20, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Paris, January 27, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Munich, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Berlin, February 1913 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Berlin, February 1913 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Munich, February 1913 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Stockholm, February 1913 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Vienna, February 1913 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Paris, February 17, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - New York, Chicago, Boston, February 17, 1913 (New York), March 24, 1913 (Chicago), April 28, 1913 (Boston) (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - Berlin, February 27, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - Kiev, after February 1913 (O.S.) (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - Budapest, March 1913 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - Vienna, March 1913 (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - The Hague, March-April 1913 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Munich, March- April 1913 (Box 13, Folder 62)
  - Vienna, March- April 1913 (Box 13, Folder 63)
  - Rome, March- June 1913 (Box 13, Folder 64)
  - St. Petersburg, March 2-30, 1913 (N.S.)/ February 17- March 17, 1913 (O.S.) (Box 13, Folder 65)
  - Moscow, March 3, 1913 (N.S.) (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Berlin, March 4, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 67)
  - Brussels, March 8, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 68)
  - Munich, March 13- end of May 1913 (Box 13, Folder 69)
  - London, March 15, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 70)
  - Munich, March 16, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 71)
  - Berlin, April 26, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 72)
  - New York, March 17, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 73)
  - Paris, March 19, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 74)
  - Berlin, Spring 1913 (Box 13, Folder 75)
  - Chicago, March 24- April 15, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 76)
  - Paris, March 31, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 77)
  - London, April 1913 (Box 13, Folder 78)
  - Budapest, April- May 1913 (Box 13, Folder 79)
  - Prague, April- May 1913 (Box 13, Folder 80)
  - Moscow, August 6, 1913 (N.S.)/ March 24, 1913 (O.S.) (Box 13, Folder 81)
  - Moscow, April 6-20, 1913 (N.S.)/ March 24- April 7, 1913 (O.S.) (Box 13, Folder 82)
  - Paris, April 14-19, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - Paris, April 14-26, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - Munich, Spring 1913 (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - Paris, April 14- June 30, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - Pittsburgh, April 24- June 30, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 87)
  - Paris, April 28- May 10, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 88)
  - Boston, April 28-May 18, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 89)
  - Brussels, April 28- June 15, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 90)
  - Prague, May- June 1913 (Box 13, Folder 91)
  - Leipzig, May- October 1913 (Box 13, Folder 92)
  - Stuttgart, May 1913 (Box 13, Folder 93)
  - Düsseldorf, May 3, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 94)
  - Mannheim, May 4, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 95)
  - Rotterdam, May 18, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 96)
  - Paris, May 19, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 97)
  - Paris, May 26, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 98)
  - Berlin, June- August 1913 (Box 13, Folder 99)
  - Paris, June 20, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 100)
  - Berlin, Summer 1913 (Box 13, Folder 101)
  - Ghent, Summer 1913 (Box 13, Folder 102)
  - London, Summer 1913 (Box 13, Folder 103)
  - Munich, June 25, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 104)
  - London, July 1913 (Box 13, Folder 105)
  - Domburg, July- August 1913 (Box 13, Folder 106)
  - Munich, August 1913 (Box 13, Folder 107)
  - Berlin, August 23, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - Moscow, after August 1913 (O.S.) (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - Berlin, September 1913 (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - Budapest, September 1913 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Stockholm, September 1913 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - Berlin, September 1-20, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - Budapest, Fall 1913 (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Berlin, October 1913 (Box 13, Folder 115)
  - Berlin, October 1913 (Box 13, Folder 116)
  - Berlin, October- November 1913 (Box 13, Folder 117)
  - Cologne, October- November 1913 (Box 13, Folder 118)
  - Brussels, October 4-27, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 119)
  - Dresden, October 9, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - Milan, October 10- December 10, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - London, October 12, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Paris, October 27, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - St. Petersburg, October 28, 1913 (N.S.)/ October 15, 1913 (O.S.) (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Berlin, November 1913 (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - Berlin, November 1913 (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - St. Petersburg, November 1913 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Vienna, November- December 1913 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Firenze, November 1913 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - St. Petersburg, November 5, 1913 (N.S.)/ October 23, 1913 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Amsterdam, November 7- December 8, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Paris, November 15, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Paris, November 17, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - St. Petersburg, November 10, 1913 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Berlin, December 1913 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Berlin, December 1913 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Moscow, December 1913 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Vienna, December 1913- January 1914 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Paris, December 15, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Brighton, December 16, 1913- January 14, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - London, Winter 1913 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Christiana, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Kiev, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Berlin, January 1914 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Berlin, January 1914 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Budapest, January 1914 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Dresden, January 1914 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - London, January 1914 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Vienna, January 1914 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Vienna, January- February 1914 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Moscow, January- February 1914 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Paris, January 6, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Moscow, January 8- February 13, 1914 (N.S.)/ December 26, 1913-January 31, 1914 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - New York, January 12, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Cologne, January 30-February 15, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Berlin, February 1914 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Budapest, February-March 1914 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Prague, February-March 1914 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Prague, February-March 1914 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Rome, February 1914 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Vienna, February-March 1914 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Rome, February-June 1914 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Berlin, February-July 1914 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Bremen, February 1, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - New York, February 2, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Paris, February 9, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Paris, February 23, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Cologne, March 1914 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - London, March-April 1914 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Moscow, March-April 1914 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Paris, March 1, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Paris, March 2, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Brussels, March 7, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - New York, March 12, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Tokyo, March 14-28, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Berlin, March 20, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Paris, March 23, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Düsseldorf, March 28, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Frankfurt, April 1914 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Berlin, April 1914 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - London, April- May 1914 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - St. Petersburg, April- May 3, 1914 (N.S.)/ ?-April 20, 1914 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Rome, April-May 1914 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Paris, April 6, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Berlin, April 12, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - Paris, April 13- June 30, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - Berlin, April 16, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - London, April 18-May 9, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - Paris, April 20- May 2, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 64)
  - Paris, April 20- May 3, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 65)
  - Venice, April 23, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 66)
  - Pittsburgh, April 30- June 30, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 67)
  - Berlin, May 1914 (Box 14, Folder 68)
  - Amsterdam, May- June 1914 (Box 14, Folder 69)
  - Berlin, May- June 1914 (Box 14, Folder 70)
  - Prague, May-June 1914 (Box 14, Folder 71)
  - Amsterdam, May 3, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 72)
  - Paris, May 4-16, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 73)
  - London, May 8, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 74)
  - Düsseldorf, May 9, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 75)
  - Brussels, May 9- November 2, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 76)
  - Paris, May 11, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 77)
  - Paris, May 13-27, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 78)
  - Malmö, May 15, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 79)
  - Paris, May 16, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 80)
  - Brussels, May 16- June 7, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 81)
  - Milan, May 20- June 10, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 82)
  - Munich, May 23- October 1914 (Box 14, Folder 83)
  - Munich, May 30- October 1, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 84)
  - Berlin, June 1914 (Box 14, Folder 85)
  - Berlin, June 1914 (Box 14, Folder 86)
  - London, June- July 1914 (Box 14, Folder 87)
  - Paris, June 8, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 88)
  - London, June 12- July 2, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 89)
  - Paris, June 17, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 90)
  - Paris, June 20, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 91)
  - Berlin, Summer 1914 (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - Munich, Summer 1914 (Box 14, Folder 93)
  - Düsseldorf, June 27, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 94)
  - London, July 1914 (Box 14, Folder 95)
  - Domburg, July- August 1914 (Box 14, Folder 96)
  - Paris, July 3, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 97)
  - Berlin, August- October 1914 (Box 14, Folder 98)
  - New York, October 10, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 99)
  - Amsterdam, November 1, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 100)
  - New York, December 9, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 101)
  - Petrograd, late 1914 (Box 14, Folder 102)
  - London, Winter 1914 (Box 14, Folder 103)
  - Amsterdam, December 22, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 104)
  - Vienna, December 31, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 105)
  - Moscow, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 106)
  - Petrograd, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 107)
  - New York, January 12, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 108)
  - New York, January 20, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 109)
  - Rotterdam, January 31- February 28, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 110)
  - Rome, February-June 1915 (Box 14, Folder 111)
  - New York, February 1, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 112)
  - New York, February 23, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 113)
  - London, March 1915 (Box 14, Folder 114)
  - Petrograd, March 3, 1915 (N.S.)/ February 18, 1915 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - Moscow, April 5, 1915 (N.S.)/ March 23, 1915 (O.S.) (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - London, June- July 1915 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - London, June 15, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - San Fransisco, SUmmer 1915 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Berlin, October- December 1915 (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Amsterdam, October 3-25, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 121)
  - London, November 1915 (Box 14, Folder 122)
  - London, November- December 1915 (Box 14, Folder 123)
  - London, December 1915- January 1915 (Box 14, Folder 124)
  - New York, December 12, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Brussels, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - New York, January 1916 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Petrograd, January 1, 1916 (N.S.)/ December 1, 1915 (O.S.) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Paris, January 15, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - New York, February 8, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - London, March 1916 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Moscow, March 1916 (O.S.) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - New York, March 13-25, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - The Hague, March 17, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - New York, April 25, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Philadelphia, May 17, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Munich, May 20- October 31, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Berlin, July 1916 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Paris, October 15, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Berlin, November 1916 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Moscow, November 1916 (O.S.) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Petrograd, December 10, 1916- January 14, 1917 (N.S.)/ November 29, 1916- January 1, 1917 (O.S.) (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - New York, December 14, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Wiesbaden, March- April 1917 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Paris, April 16, 1918 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - New York, May 3, 1918 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Paris, June 11, 1919 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Amsterdam, February 22, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Paris, May 30, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Paris, June 13, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Amsterdam, October 19, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Paris, November 17-18, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Paris, July 4, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Berlin, Autumn 1922 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Munich, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Paris, May 7-8, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Moscow, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Sweden, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Amsterdam, July 6- September 30, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - New York, December 3, 1963- January 4, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Paris, April 11- May 10, 1912 (?) (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Brussels (omitted), August 5-29, 1906 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Brussels (omitted), June 15- July 8, 1907 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Paris (omitted), Winter 1910 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - New York (omitted), December 14, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Paris (omitted), October 30, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - New York (omitted), April 11- May 10, 1912 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Düsseldorf (omitted), 1913 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Prague (omitted), 1913 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Berlin (omitted), March 27, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Berlin (omitted), November 1913 (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Cologne (omitted), May 1914 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - New York (omitted), November 3, 1914 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - Stockholm (misc. catologues) (omitted), 1916 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Amsterdam (oversized), February- March 1904 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Amsterdam (oversized), August 1905 (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Amsterdam (oversized), June 1911 (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Dresden (oversized), May 1912 (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Paris (oversized), May 1912 (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - Düsseldorf (oversized), 1913 (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Germany (oversized), January- February 1913 (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - Malmö (oversized), May 1914 (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - Amsterdam (oversized), May- June 1914 (Box 15, Folder 58)
  - Munich (oversized), Summer 1919 (Box 15, Folder 59)
  - Amsterdam (oversized), October 1915 (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - various European catalogs (oversized), 1905-1959 (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - Artist catalog index (oversized) (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - Information Sheet: Modern Art Exhibitions: selected Catalogue Documentation, 1900-1916 (Box 15, Folder 63)
- Expressionism: Art and Idea, III.
  Published posthumously in 1987, Expressionism: Art and Idea is a survey of Expressionist painting from its origins in the early 1900s up through the 1970s. This series contains Dr. Gordon's painting inventories from various countries and periods of Expressionism, as well as images used in his book.
  - Inventory of Paintings, 1.
    This inventory of artists was created by Dr. Gordon while researching his book on Expressionism. The inventory is arranged chronologically and geographically.
    - Romanticism
      - Caspar David Friedrich, 1774-1840 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Phillip Otto Runge, 1777-1810 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Pre-Raphaelites
      - Ford Maddox Brown, 1821-1893 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Sir Edward Burne-Jone, 1883-1898 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - William Holman Hunt, 1827-1910 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Sir John Everett Millais, 1829-1896 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Dante Gabriel Rossetti, 1828-1882 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - George Frederic Watts, 1817-1904 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - German, English, Scandinavian Naturalism
      - Arnold Boecklin, 1827-1901 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Constantin Guys, 1802-1892 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Franz von Lenbach, 1836-1904 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Wilhelm Liebl, 1844-1900 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Hans von Marees, 1837-1887 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Adolf von Menzel, 1815-1905 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - John Ruskin, 1819-1900 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Walter Sickert, 1860-1942 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Alfred Stevens, 1823-1906 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - Joseph M. W. Turner, 1775-1851 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - Anders Zorn, 1860-1921 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - French School
      - Rodolphe Bresdin, 1825-1885 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - Michele Cammarano, 1835-1930 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - Theodore Chasseriau, 1819-1856 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - Pierre Cot, 1837-1883 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - Gustave Courbet, 1819-1877 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - Eduard Degas, 1834-1917 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - Giovanni Fattori, 1825-1908 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Silvestro Lega, 1826-1895 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - Eduoard Manet, 1832-1883 (Box 16, Folder 28)
      - Adolphe Monticelli, 1824-1886 (Box 16, Folder 29)
      - Jean Francois Millet, 1814-1875 (Box 16, Folder 30)
      - Pierre Puvis de Chavannes, 1824-1898 (Box 16, Folder 31)
      - Gioacchino Toma, 1836-1891 (Box 16, Folder 32)
      - Telemaco Signorini, 1835-1901 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Post-Impressionism
      - Paul Baum, 1859-1932 (Box 16, Folder 34)
      - Aubrey Beardsley, 1873-1899 (Box 16, Folder 35)
      - Emile Bernard, 1868-1941 (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Paul Cezanne, 1839-1906 (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - Maurice Denis, 1870-1943 (Box 16, Folder 38)
      - James Ensor, 1860-1949 (Box 16, Folder 39)
      - Paul Gauguin, 1848-1903 (Box 16, Folder 40)
      - Gustav Klimt, 1862-1918 (Box 16, Folder 41)
      - Max Klinger, 1857-1920 (Box 16, Folder 42)
      - Ferdinand Holder, 1853-1918 (Box 16, Folder 43)
      - Max Lieberman, 1847-1935 (Box 16, Folder 44)
      - Gustave Moreau, 1826-1898 (Box 16, Folder 45)
      - Edvard Munch, 1863-1944 (Box 16, Folder 46)
      - Odilon Redon, 1840-1916 (Box 16, Folder 47)
      - Henri Rousseau, 1844-1910 (Box 16, Folder 48)
      - Paul Serusier, 1863-1927 (Box 16, Folder 49)
      - Georges Seurat, 1859-1890 (Box 16, Folder 50)
      - Franz von Stuck, 1863-1928 (Box 16, Folder 51)
      - Hans Thoma, 1839-1924 (Box 16, Folder 52)
      - Jan Toorop, 1858-1928 (Box 16, Folder 53)
      - Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec, 1864-1901 (Box 16, Folder 54)
      - Felix Valloton, 1925-1965 (Box 16, Folder 55)
      - Henri van de Velde, 1863-1957 (Box 16, Folder 56)
      - Carolus Verhaeren, 1908-1956 (Box 16, Folder 57)
      - Edouard Vuillard, 1868-1940 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - 1905-1914 Period, Dutch
      - Piet Mondrian, 1874-1944 (Box 16, Folder 59)
      - Kees van Dongen, 1877-1968 (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - 1905-1914 Period, English
      - Augustus E. John, 1879-1961 (Box 16, Folder 61)
    - 1905-1914 Period, French
      - Pierre Bonnard, 1867-1947 (Box 16, Folder 62)
      - Georges Braque, 1882-1963 (Box 16, Folder 63)
      - Marc Chagall, 1887-1985 (Box 16, Folder 64)
      - Robert Delaunay, 1884-1941 (Box 16, Folder 65)
      - Andre Derain, 1880-1954 (Box 16, Folder 66)
      - Marcel Duchamp, 1887-1968 (Box 16, Folder 67)
      - Raoul Dufy, 1877-1953 (Box 16, Folder 68)
      - Roger de la Fresnaye, 1885-1925 (Box 16, Folder 69)
      - Othon Friesze, 1879-1949 (Box 16, Folder 70)
      - Albert Gleizes, 1881-1953 (Box 16, Folder 71)
      - Frank Kupka, 1871-1957 (Box 16, Folder 72)
      - Marie Laurencin, 1883-1956 (Box 16, Folder 73)
      - Fernand Leger, 1881-1955 (Box 16, Folder 74)
      - Henri Manguin, 1874-1949 (Box 16, Folder 75)
      - Pierre Albert Marquet, 1875-1947 (Box 16, Folder 76)
      - Henri Matisse, 1869-1954 (Box 16, Folder 77)
      - Jean Metzinger, 1883-1956 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Amadeo Modigliani, 1884-1920 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Luc-Albert Moreau, 1882-1933 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Constant Permeke, 1886-1952 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Francis Picabia, 1879-1953 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Georges Rouault, 1871-1958 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Andre Dunoyer de Segonzac, 1884-1974 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Jacques Villon, 1875-1963 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Maurice de Vlaminck, 1876-1958 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - 1905-1914 Period, German
      - Max Beckmann, 1884-1950 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Lovis Corinth, 1858-1925 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Lyonel Feininger, 1871-1956 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Erich Heckel, 1883-1970 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Karl Hofer, 1878-1955 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Alexei Jawlensky, 1864-1941 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Alexander Kanoldt, 1881-1939 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Wassily Kandinsky, 1866-1944 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Ernst L. Kirchner, 1880-1938 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Paul Klee, 1879-1940 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Oskar Kokoschka, 1886-1980 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Kaethe Kollwitz, 1862-1945 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - August Macke, 1887-1914 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Franz Marc, 1880-1916 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Paula Medersohn-Becker, 1876-1907 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Ludwig Meidner, 1884-1966 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Otto Muller, 1874-1930 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Emil Nolde, 1867-1956 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Christian Rohlfs, 1849-1938 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Karl Schmidt-Rottluff, 1884-1976 (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Max Slevogt, 1868-1932 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - 1905-1914 Period, Italian
      - Giacomo Balla, 1871-1958 (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Umberto Boccioni, 1882-1916 (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - Carlo Carra, 1881-1966 (Box 17, Folder 33)
      - Giorgio de Chirico, 1888-1978 (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - Gino Severini, 1883-1966 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - 1905-1914 Period, Spanish
      - Joaquin Sorolla, 1863-1923 (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - Juan Gris, 1887-1927 (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - Pablo Picasso, 1881-1973 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 1905-1914 Period, Russian
      - Russian Artists (Box 18, Folder 2)
        This folder contains cards pertaining to the following artists: Nathan Altman (1889-1970); Yury Annenkov (1889-1974); Alexander Benois (1870-1960); Victor Borissov-Mussatov (1870-1905); David Burliuk (1882-1967); Vladimir Burliuk (1886-1917); Marc Chagall (1887-1985); Ja Chernikov (???); Mikalojus Ciurlionis (1875-1911); Matislav Dobuzhinsky (1875-1957); Alexandra Exter (1882-1949); Robert Falk (1886-1958); Vladimir Favorsky (1886-1964); Pavel Filonov (1883-1941); Naum Gabo (1890-1977); Alexei Gan (1889-1942); Natalia Goncharova (1881-1962); Vassily Kandinsky (1866-1944); S. Kliushnikov (needs dates); Ivan Klium (1873-1943); Pyotr Konchalovsky (1876-1956); Pavel Kusnetsov (1878-1968); Mikhail Larionov (1881-1964); (Anton?) Lavinsky (1893-1968); Isaac Levitan (1860-1900); Lazar (El) Lissitzky (1890-1941); Ilya Mashkov (1884-1944); Kasimir Medunetsky (1899-1935); Nikolai Miliuti (dates unknown?); Vassily Miliuti (dates unknown?); Pyotr Miturich (1887-1956); Leonid Pasternak (1862-1945); Kuzma Petrov-Vodkin (1878-1939); Anton (Noton) Pevsner (1886-1962); Yury Pimenov (1903-1977); Niko Pirosmanishvili (1862-1918); Liubov Popova (1889-1924); Ivan Puni (1892-1956); Ilya Repin (1844-1930); Alexander Rodchenko (1891-1956); Olga Rosanova (1886-1918); Nikolai Sapunov (1880-1912); Martiros Saryan (1880-1972); Valentin Serov (1865-1911); Konstantin Somov (1869-1939); Vassily Surikov (1848-1912); Vladimir Tatlin (1885-1953); Nadezhda Udaltsova (1886-1961); Mikhail Vrubel (1856-1910); and Miscellaneous Works
      - Kasimir Malevich, 1878-1935 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Postwar Period
      - Hans Arp, 1886-1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Francis Bacon, 1909-1992 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Salvador Dali, 1904-1989 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Otto Dix, 1891-1969 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Max Ernst, 1891-1976 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Georges Grosz, 1893-1959 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Rene Magritte, 1898-1967 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Andre Masson, 1896-1987 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Joan Miro, 1893-1983 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Giorgio Morandi, 1890-1964 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Ben Nicholson, 1894-1982 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Amedee Ozenfant, 1886-1966 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Kurt Schwitters, 1887-1948 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Chaim Soutine, 1893-1943 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Graham Sutherland, 1903-1980 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Misc. (Postcards)
      - Misc. (Postcards) (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Images, 2.
    These photographs of exhibition catalogs and artwork were used by Dr. Gordon while researching his book on Expressionism.
    - MOMA Research, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 64)